Profile

For the past 3 years I have been a hobbyist programmer primarily working with Javascript, MySQL and HTML/CSS.

I have experience in programming in both front and back ends, however I have discovered an affinity for backend programming. I was fortunate enough to be commissioned by my current employer to create a custom reporting and tracking software that was successfully launched to over 150 employees.

Experience

PROGRAMMER, HUWIZ INC. - MAY 2021 - PRESENT

Responsibilities:

- Sole programmer on an application designed by committee
- Responsible for the full stack
- Utilized HTML / TailwindCSS / Javascript / Vue.JS / Node & Express / PassportJS
- Creation REST APIs
- Creation and maintenance of a MySQL database
- Give realistic timeframes for work to be completed
- Bug fixing

PROJECT MANAGER, HUWIZ INC. – MARCH 2022 - PRESENT Responsibilities:

- Daily communication with multiple clients worldwide.
- Ensuring budget and resource allocation aligns with clients goals.
- Offering suggestions based on experience regarding testing focus.
- Ensuring that goals are met.
- Conducting employee reviews and direct interventions when required.
- Maintain documentation internally regarding billing, HR, and testing.
- Daily kickoff meetings with teams of analysts.

QA TEAM LEADER, HUWIZ INC. – MARCH 2021 - MARCH 2022

Responsibilities:

- Daily meetings with multiple teams of analysts.
- Ensuring testing goals are achieved in the allotted time.
- In conjunction with the Project manager, attend and participate in meetings with clients.
- Monitor the daily activities of analysts ensuring that their productivity is as expected.
- Point of contact for all analyst questions regarding the projects I led.
- Maintained documentation, such as test cases.

FQA ANALYST, HUWIZ INC. – APRIL 2020 - MARCH 2021 Responsibilities:

- Verified all aspects regarding functionality across multiple projects.
- Provided through, and detailed reports of all issues encountered.
- Participated in daily team meetings.
- Working with multiple analysts when required on multiplayer projects.

QA ANALYST, STINGRAY DIGITAL - 2016-2018

Responsibilities:

- Attended SCRUM meetings to ensure testing aligned with development goals.
- Tested multiple products including websites, music videos, mobile applications, and proprietary hardware.
- Worked with a team of 8 analysts daily to ensure that overlap did not occur during tests.
- Maintained internal documentation, including application tech documents used in trainings, and test cases.

Education

John Abbott College - Python programming FreeCodeCamp - Responsive web design certification FreeCodeCamp - Backend development and API certification

Skills

- Microsoft office suite, google office suite, and MacOS Office suite
- Operating systems (Windows, MacOS, Linux command line)
- Relational databases
- Multiple programming languages (Javascript, CSS / TailwindCSS, HTML, Python, SQL)
- Bilingual (English / French)
- Leadership and management